<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hitoshi Takeuchi&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hitoshi Takeuchi&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja-JP</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey of Self-care</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/journey-of-self-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/journey-of-self-care/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜“Journey of Self-care”(2022)＞
Journey of Self-care, HD, 8min.39sec., 2022
Fence Line Text, Journey of Self-care Installation ver, 2022
In order to open up a perspective on self-care, I went to Okinawa and attempted to generate my own way of speaking by listening to the narratives of sculptors in Okinawa. Through the production of artworks, I will confirm whether or not his attempts are valid as a free indirect speech method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excitation of Narratives</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/eon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/eon/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜EoN (Research Project, 2021)＞
EoN (Excitation of Narratives) is a research project artists and researchers introduce and translate books about essayfilm. We explore narrative techniques and develop new ways of telling stories. And we summarize our research and present video works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ART RESEARCH ONLINE</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/art-research-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/art-research-online/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜ART RESEARCH ONLINE (Research Project, 2020)＞
With the expansion of the new coronavirus infection (COVID-19), exhibitions and other events have been cancelled or postponed, and I am planning an online research project that relates to art for personal space. It&amp;rsquo;s a project where people from various fields can introduce their papers, read books, and present their works.
https://www.artresearchonline.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pale View of Shibuya River</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/a-pale-view-of-shibuya-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/a-pale-view-of-shibuya-river/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜“A Pale View of Shibuya River” (Installation, 2019)＞
It is a landscape of the past where Shibuya River flowed under Cat Street. Before the Tokyo Olympics 1964, the river around there is forced to flow underground using a conduit and no water flow can be seen on the ground.
Dates: September 20, 2019 - September 29
Location: BLOCK HOUSE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAN Paintings</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/gan-paintings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/gan-paintings/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜“GAN Paintings” (Oil on canvas, 2019)＞
I’m interested in how GAN(Generative Adversarial Network) can affect the transparency of photograph and the opacity of painting in the post-truth era. I discover new motif that I have never seen. And latent spaces seem to be a good place to go on a search. Theoretically latent spaces is only a collection of diverse vector space models, but in the process of interpolation in latent spaces, there is a poetic image with technical problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Melancholy Mountain</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/the-melancholy-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/the-melancholy-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜“The Melancholy Mountain” (Video Installation, 2018)＞
The Melancholy Mountain is a multi display work by real time rendering. This procedure mountain is drawn with a wireframe and not a landscape but gamescape. We are only looking at the wireframe mesh deformed by the algorithm. The landscape of a digital image today may be the landscape of simulated virtual images by code no longer what we think is landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nomadic AI Agents</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/nomadic-ai-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/nomadic-ai-agents/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜“Nomadic AI Agents” (Installation, 2018)＞
Nomadic AI Agents are practically useless AI agents. The framework uses ML-Agents, a machine learning environment of Unity which is a game engine. Through the learning Python script, the library TensorFlow for machine learning and the executable file created by Unity are linked to simulate, learn the action of ball agent entering into the box while using obstacles in the scene, it will start acting as if its will lived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Mountain</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/the-secret-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/the-secret-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜“The Secret Mountain” (Video Installation, 2018)＞
The Secret Mountain is a multi display work and also VR work. This typical mountain object is indeed an unwavering entity capable of reviewing poetry and is a poet with a unique personality. The viewer looks at the landscape that changes in real time along with poetry and at the same time is involved with objects containing various contexts, meanings, images that are rolling in chaos while wandering through the terrain world, We will read the environment and algorithm of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profile</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/profile/</guid>
      <description>Artist, Programmer, Researcher
Born 1985 in Tokyo, Japan. Bachelor of Intermedia Art, Tokyo University of the Arts. I’m mostly interested in human perception and media aesthetics theory, and I create video works and interactive installations. In the unique conditions of media technologies, I present a variety of works that critically redefines human sensory experience and existence.
[Contact]
htakeuchi.info@gmail.com
[Exhibition|Screening]
‘22・OPEN SITE 7, Tokyo Arts and Space|Tokyo
‘19・BHVR, BLOCK HOUSE|Tokyo
‘19・Eureka, GALLERY WATER|Tokyo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intersubjective Space</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/intersubjective-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/intersubjective-space/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜&amp;rdquo;Intersubjective Space&amp;rdquo; (VR Installation, 2016)＞
The main concept of this work about asymmetry of media and space information. Activate the reciprocating movement of imagining the space from the image and memorizing the experience of the space as an image.
Dates: July 17, 2016
Location: AKIBA_SQUARE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaudible Conversation</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/inaudible-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/inaudible-conversation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜&amp;rdquo;Inaudible Conversation&amp;rdquo; (Installation, 2014)＞
It is a work that tried to visualize the conversation spatially. The word is displayed in real-time on the transparent screen.
Dates: July 6, 2014 - July 7
Location: Sogakudo Concert</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation Piece</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/conversation-piece/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/conversation-piece/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜&amp;rdquo;Conversation Piece&amp;rdquo; (Installation, 2013)＞
It is a work that projected pieces of landscape on a spatially arranged acrylic board. From a certain point of view you can appreciate it as a painting.
Dates: July 23, 2013 - July 26
Location: Tokyo University of the Arts
Location: KINOHAUS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethel House</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/bethel-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/bethel-house/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜&amp;rdquo;Bethel House&amp;rdquo; (Video Installation, 2013)＞
In 1978, several people with mental disorders, who had been discharged from Red Cross Hospital in Urakawa, formed a survivors&amp;rsquo; group. They moved into an old, abandoned church house and started living together. It was named Bethel House in 1984, and became the cornerstone of advocacy movement of people with mental disorders. It is a video work about the history and current activities of Bethel House.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/acceptance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/acceptance/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜&amp;rdquo;Acceptance&amp;rdquo; (Video Installation, 2011)＞
It is a documentary about a nuclear power plant worker whose home is located within a distance of 20 kilometers from the Fukushima nuclear power plant and his life at the Toride city bicycle racecourse evacuation center.
Location: Voices of Fukushima</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hope house</title>
      <link>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/hope-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitoshitakeuchi.com/blog/hope-house/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ＜&amp;rdquo;hope house&amp;rdquo; (Video Installation, 2011)＞
There is a hospice called hope house that takes care of the last days of those who have no relatives in Tokyo. It is a video work about a man&amp;rsquo;s life of hope house, and ceremony for the end of analog television broadcasting in Japan.
Dates: July 24, 2012
Location: KINOHAUS</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>